MARISSA SANATI

Calabasas, CA · (805) 796-9222

Msanati0615@gmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/marissa-sanati

Skilled in enterprise IT sourcing and procurement, vendor management, contract negotiation and distribution/supply chain management. Identification and implementation of potential cost/efficiency improvements on a micro and macro scale. Experience in software, hardware, cloud and SaaS contracting, and negotiating with enterprise level IT suppliers.

EXPERIENCE

OCTOBER 2017 - PRESENT STRATEGIC SOURCING MANAGER, IT SOFTWARE

ANTHEM, INC.

- Responsible for the execution and implementation of IT software, IT hardware, and IT consulting services related to Artificial Intelligence, Robotic Process Automation, Cloud storage, mainframe database management projects, including the management of enterprise suppliers such as Oracle, Microsoft and SAP.
- Created and implemented process and procedures throughout the procurement organization to transition all software from an Anthem owned and managed data center to a third party owned and managed facility and cloud space.
- Ran full cycle RFP to evaluate Value Added Resellers within the software and hardware space throughout the enterprise; resulted in a consolidation of the number of VARS, and increased rebate and discount percentages affecting over \$21M in annual spend.
- Subject Matter Expert on the IT software team for all software proof of concepts (POCs) throughout the organization.
- Build and maintain strong business and technical relationships with internal customers and key suppliers including legal, IT, and risk management.
- Led and organized the design, implementation and training for an enterprise-wide sourcing tool used throughout all areas to consolidate sourcing and spend data for the organization.
- Increased spend portfolio responsibility from \$14M in 2018 to over \$150M in 2020.
- Responsible for \$4.7M in software specific savings through various consolidation and process improvement initiatives in 2020.
- Assist in recruiting, training and mentoring new team members and various waves of intern programs throughout the year.

MARCH 2015 – OCTOBER 2017 ASSOCIATE HUMAN RESOURCES CONSULTANT

ANTHEM, INC.

- Responsible for data collection and management of high level and enterprise-wide HR projects.
- Facilitated government mandated training for over 800 managers in CA, ensure all managers stay compliant with CA state law throughout the year.
- Participated in Open Enrollment training and events to assist members with OE and questions.
- Present Anthem Culture Presentation to all new associates; receive monthly reports to compile lists of all new hires and ensure 100% enrollment and completion.

• Analyze, research and coordinate data for ad hoc reports for internal HR and for external business use.

JULY 2013 – MARCH 2015 HUMAN RESOURCES GENERALIST

IDRIVE, INC.

- Reduced employee turnover from 51% in Q2 of 2013, to 33% in Q1 of 2014
- Created cost benefit analysis to analyze hiring and training needs, immigration decisions, and asset attainment.
- Developed a recruitment and interview strategy with all hiring managers to more efficiently and effectively organize, interview and select candidates.
- Facilitated the immigration process for employees in various stages of naturalization, preparing legal documents, and completing legal requirements to keep immigration status' valid and active.
- Transitioned entire company to new benefits provider, from an HMO to option-based policy including HMO and PPO choices.

JULY 2012 - JULY 2013

RECRUITING MANAGER

CAPTAIN MARKETING

- Responsible for full cycle recruitment for positions throughout the company, including marketing, sales and management front office positions.
- Utilized a wide variety of web based and social media tools, including Glassdoor, LinkedIn, etc.
- Facilitated each step of the interview process, including resume screening, phone interviews, and in-person interviews.
- Coordinated all new-hire orientation and training processes.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN LIBERAL STUDIES UNIVERSITY OF LA VERNE

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN LEADERSHIP MANAGEMENT UNIVERSITY OF LA VERNE